Guide to the Don Patinkin Papers, 1870-1995
Don Patinkin papers 1870-1995
- Correspondence, 1930-1995and undated (Bulk 1950-1995)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1995 (Bulk 1987-1995)and undated
    - Conference, Denmark, 1987, July-1990, Feb.
    - Conference, Stockholm, 1987, Jan.-Nov.
    - Currie, Lauchlin, 1988, Feb.-1994, Jan.
    - Czechoslovakia, 1991, Feb.-1992, June
    - Darity, William, 1987, Sept.-1991, Sept.
    - Eckhaus, Richard, 1988, May
    - Econometric Society, 1989, Dec.-1995, Aug.
    - The Economic Journal:
      - 1993, Aug.-1994, Oct.
      - Chronology, 1990, July-1993, Aug.
    - The Economist: Keynes, 1990, Mar.-1994, July
    - Edward Elgar Publishing, 1987, Feb.-1994, Nov.
    - Efroymson, Clarence, 1986, Apr.-1987, Aug.
    - Emmett, Ross B., 1989, July-Sept.
    - Entov, 1989, June
    - European University Institute, 1988, June-1992, Mar.
    - Farmiloe, T. M., 1989, Sept.-1992, June
    - Fase, M. M .G., 1988, Aug.-1994, May
    - Fischer, Stanley, (4 folders)
      - 1982-1989
    - Fischer, Stanley (cont.): (Box 54)
      - 1989-1991
      - 1992-1993
      - Russia, 1992, Dec.-1993, June
    - Fitoussi, Annie, 1987-1991
    - Flemming, John, 1989, Oct.-1990
    - Fogel, Robert, 1991, Aug.-1992, Aug.
    - Friedman, 1992, Sept.
    - Fusfeld, Daniel R., 1986, Dec.-1989, May
    - Gale, Douglas, 1987, May
    - Glasner, David, 1991, Apr.-1991, May
    - Goodwin, Craufurd, 1987-1995,Jan, (8 folders)
      - 1987
      - 1988, Jan.-June
      - 1988, July- Dec.
      - 1989, Jan.-Nov.
      - 1989, Dec.-1990
      - 1991-1992
      - 1992, Nov.-1993, Dec.
    - Goodwin, Craufurd: (cont.) (Box 55)
      - 1994, Jan.-1995, Jan.
    - Grandmont, Jean Michel, 1987, June-July
    - Gresham Conference, 1994-1995,May
    - Hackohen, Mordecai, 1987, Dec.-1990, Feb.
    - Hagemann, Harald, 1987, Nov.-1988, Jan.
    - Harper and Row, 1977, June-1989, Jan.
    - Harvey Prize Fund, 1988, Apr.-1991, Apr.
    - Hellwig, Martin, 1993, Mar.-1995, Sept.
    - Helsinki, 1987, Apr.-1989, Oct.
    - Henriksson, Rolf, 1990, May-1994, May
    - History of Economics Society Bulletin (HES), 1989, June-July
    - Hicks, John, 1945, Nov.-1988, Nov.
    - Hirsch, E. D., 1990, Dec.-1991, Mar.
    - Hirsch, Werner, 1989, July-1990, Jan.
    - Howitt, Peter, 1985, Jan.-1993, Nov., (2 folders)
    - Hebrew University:
      - General, 1987, May-1991, Mar.
      - Evolution, 1986, Sept.-Oct.
      - Payment fund, undated
      - Research fund, 1986, Nov.-1989, June
      - Retirement, 1986, May-1989, Sept.
      - Sabbatical, 1987, Dec.-1989, Aug.
    - Humphrey, Tom M., 1987, June-1994, Feb. (Box 56)
    - Hutchison, Terence, 1987, Apr.-1988, Sept.
    - International Economic Association (IEA.), 1987, July-1992, Feb.
    - International Executive Committee, 1989, Aug.-1991, Oct.
    - IEA India Conference
    - IEA Moscow
    - IEA Moscow Congress
    - IEA Seed
    - Indirect Convertibility
    - Institute of Economic Affairs
    - Introduction to Economy,1987
    - Iriya- Jerusalem Municipality
    - Israeli Inflation - Correspondence
    - "Israeli Inflation" - IEA Paper
    - Johnson, Peter
    - Jonung, Lars, (2 folders)
    - Jonung Manuscripts, (2 folders)
    - Kahane, Neir (Box 57)
    - Keynesian Cross - Correspondence
    - Keynes Lecture - Correspondence
    - Keynes Lecture - Journals
    - Klausinger, Hanjjoig
    - Klein, Lawrence, 1989-1995
    - Kohn, Neir, 1989-1990
    - Kop,1989
    - Korea, 1977-1996
    - Laidler, David 1982-1994, (3 folders)
    - Levy, Margot 1987-1992, (2 folders)
    - Linda, Thornton, 1989 (Box 58)
    - Lindbeck, Assar, 1986-1991
    - Littleboy, Brace, 1987-1988
    - Marglin, Steve, 1987
    - Marris R., 1987-1990
    - Marshall High School,1989
    - Matthews, Prof. R. C., 1990
    - Mayer, Tom, 1989-1990
    - McDonnell Fellowship,1987
    - McGill, 1989-1990
    - Meade, James, 1987-1993
    - Meade Conference, 1990-1991
    - Mehta, Ghanshyam, 1987
    - Meltzer, 1980-1994
    - Merton, Robert K., 1987-1991
    - Mexico, 1988-1992
    - Miller, Edward M., 1983-1989
    - Mints, Lloyd Wynn, 1987-1988
    - Money, Interest, and Prices (MIP) - Introduction List, 1989, April-May
    - M.I.P. - Thank You's, 1989-1990
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1994
    - Miscellaneous Professional,1988-1993, (2 folders)
    - MIT Press, Layzer,1989 (Box 59)
    - MIT Press - others, 1988-1990
    - MIT Press- Terry Vaughn, 1988-1993
    - Mizpah, 1989-1990
    - Moggridge 1978-1993, (3 folders)
    - Mongiovi, Gary, 1989
    - Moscow School, 1992-1993
    - Moscow School, 1993-1994
    - Moscow School Exams,1993
    - Moscow School Recommendations, 1994-1995
    - Mundlak, 1992
    - National Science Foundation,1989
    - Nell, Edward J., 1992
    - Neutrality of Money, 1987-1989
    - The New Palgrave, 1983-1987
    - Newman, 1984-1994
    - O'Donnell, Rod, 1987-1995
    - Ostroy, 1989-1992
    - Pardes, Ilana, 1991
    - Pasinetti, Luigi, 1988-1994 (Box 60)
    - Patinkin, Chair, 1991-1992
    - Patinkin, Conference, 1989-1990
    - Patinkin, Personal 1987-1994, (2 folders)
    - Perlman, Mark, 1993
    - Correspondence, 1941-1995 (Bulk 1987-1995)and undated
    - Pittsburgh,1987
    - Plessner, Yakir, 1994
    - Plosser, Charles, 1992-1994
    - Poland,1991
    - Prais, S.J., 1988-1990
    - Publishers, 1987-1992
    - Purchases, 1985-1992
    - Reading Lists, 1988-1989
    - Recommendations, 1989-1995
    - Recktenwald, Horst, 1987-1990
    - Referee's Reports, 1987-1992
    - Reich, Hermann, 1987
    - Research Grant 1989-1993, (2 folders)
    - Reviews - Anticipations,1982-1986 (Box 61)
    - Reviews - Chicago Essays,1981-1986
    - Richmond, 1990-1994
    - Robinson, Austin, 1990
    - Rosovsky, 1987-1993
    - Rothschild Prize, 1989-1995
    - Rubinstein, Aryah, 1987-1993
    - Russia, 1989-1996
    - Rymes, 1986-1993
    - Salant, Walter, 1987
    - Samuelson, Paul, 1993-1995
    - Santa Barbara, 1987-1992
    - Savastano and Chadha,1990
    - Scandinavian Journal of Economics, 1987-1991
    - Schumpeter, 1991-1992
    - Sebastiani, Mario, 1987-1989
    - Sen, Amartya, 1985-1994
    - Shefet, Joseph
    - Shackle, G. F. S., 1990-1991
    - Shell, Marc, 1989-1990
    - Siena, 1988-1995
    - Skidelsky, Lord, 1986-1992
    - Smithin, John, 1985-1987 (Box 62)
    - Solow, Robert, 1987-1990
    - Spain,1994
    - Svensen, Lars, 1989
    - Steiger, Otto, 1987-1989
    - Steindl, 1986-1989
    - Stigler, G. J., 1987-1991
    - Stockholm, 1990-1991
    - Taiwan, 1989-1993
    - Telcer, Lester, 1988-1990
    - Tobin, James, 1991-1993
    - Tochtermann, 1987-1990
    - Trescott, Paul, 1987-1992
    - UCLA, Accounts, 1989-1990
    - UCLA, Evaluation,1989
    - UCLA, Jerusalem, 1988-1991
    - UCLA, Official, 1987-1994
    - Walker, 1986-1995, (2 folders)
    - Walras - Book Review, 1991-1995
    - Weintraub, E. Roy, 1987-1992
    - Wider, 1987-1993 (Box 63)
    - Winch, Donald, 1991
    - Young, Warren, 1990-1992
    - Yellin, Larry, 1991-1992
    - Zelinsky, Daniel, 1982-1992
    - Abraham, 1992, Aug.-1994, Dec.
    - Anticipations of the General Theory, 1991, Jun. 3-1992, Jan. 30
    - Argentina, 1992, Apr. 1-1993, Dec. 14
    - Arrow, 1983, Oct. 24-1995, May 10
    - ATandT, 1988, Feb. 19-1995, Feb. 13
    - Atkinson, 1993, Feb. 1-1993, Dec. 3
    - Autobiography (Hebrew),1994, Jun.-1994, Oct.
    - Banca D'Italia, 1993, Dec. 11-1994, Mar. 29
    - Barak, 1982, Sept.-1994, Nov. 21
    - Barber, William J., 1993, Aug. 10-18
    - Basel, 1993, Jan. 16-1994, Mar. 16
    - Berglas School of Economics, 1993, Dec.-1994, Jan.
    - Blackwell, 1993, Apr.-1995, Feb.
    - Blaug, Mark, 1993, Jun.-1995, Jan.
    - Blinder, Alan S., 1988, Dec.-1993, Jan.
    - Boianovsky, Mauro, 1995, Feb.-Apr.
    - Book Contracts, 1965, May-1992, July
    - Books Ordered, 1993, June-1995, Mar.
    - Bridel, Pascal, 1993, Sept.-1995, Feb.
    - California, 1994, Jan.
    - Cambridge University Press, 1992, Sept.-1995, May
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1987, Oct.-1994, June
    - Chicago Volume, 1993, June-1994, June
    - China, 1992, Dec.-1994, Aug.
    - Association for Civil Rights in Israel, 1990, Mar.-July
    - Clarke, Peter F., 1987, Mar.-1993, Oct.
    - Compensated Dollar, Correspondence, 1991-1993
    - Compensated Dollar Plan - Reactions, 1993, Nov.-1994, May
    - Conference: Socialism, 1991, Apr.
    - Copyright, 1991, July-1992, Mar.
    - Cukierman, A., 1994, Feb. 16
    - C.V. - Patinkin,1995
    - C.V.'s - Others, 1985, Mar.-1992, Jan.
    - Davidson, Paul, 1988, Aug.-1993, Sept.
    - Dimand, Robert, 1989, Aug.-1994, Jan.
    - Dostaler, Gilles, 1990, Mar.-1993, Dec. (Box 64)
    - Dowd, Kevin, 1994, Jan.-1994, July
    - Dreze, Jean, 1992, June-1992, Sept.
    - Duke University Archives, 1985, June-1995, June
    - Duke University Press, 1981, Sept.-1994, Nov.
    - Dvora Patinkin, 1988, Nov.-1995, Jan.
    - Econometric Society, 1995, Mar.-Apr.
    - Elgar, Edward, 1995, Feb.
    - European Economic Association, 1993, Aug.-1995, Sept.
    - Falk Institute, 1992, July-1994, July
    - David I. F, 1994, Aug.
    - Farmiloe, Tim, 1992, Dec.-1995, Feb.
    - Ferber, Marianne, 1993, Nov.-1994, Feb.
    - Fischer, Stanley, 1994, June-1995, Jan.
    - Fischer, Franck, 1993, May-1994, Jan.
    - Fischer, Irving - Review, 1994, Apr.-1995, June
    - Fitoussi, Jean-Paul, 1991, Jan.-1995, May
    - Flemming, John, 1993, Jan.-1993, Aug.
    - Ford, Jim, 1993, Aug.-1993, Oct.
    - Frequent Flyer, 1986, Nov.-1994, July
    - Gerrard, Bill, 1991, Mar.-1991, June
    - Goodheart, Prof. C. A. E., 1993, Dec.-1995, Mar.
    - Goodwin, Craufurd, 1995, Jan.-1995, May
    - Goodwin, Nancy, 1991, Dec.-1993, Nov.
    - Graboyes, Robert, 1990, Feb.-1995, Feb.
    - Gregg Lewis, 1993, June-1994, Jan.
    - Griliches, 1993, Feb.-1995, Jan.
    - Groenewegen, 1994, Apr.-Oct.
    - Grossman, Ed and Sue, 1990, Jan.-1995, June
    - Grossman, Herschel, 1993, Mar.-1993, June
    - Hahn, Frank H., 1983, June-1991, Dec.
    - Hammond, J. Daniel, 1978, Apr.-1994, Oct.
    - Harcourt, Geoffrey C., 1987, Jan.-1992, July
    - Heertje, Arnold, 1984, Nov.-1995, Mar.
    - Heffer and Sons, 1990, Dec.-1994, July
    - Helpman, Elhanan, 1994, Aug. 23
    - Hetzel, Robert, 1990, Oct.-1993, Aug.
    - Hirshleifer, Jack, 1989, July-1994. Jan.
    - History of Economics Society, 1994, Jan.-Nov.
    - Hollander, Samuel, 1988, Apr.-1988, Aug.
    - Hong-Kong, 1990, Mar.-1990, Sept.
    - Hoover, Kevin D., Aug. 1992-1994,July
    - Howitt, Peter, 1994, Jan.-1994, May
    - Howson, Susan, 1990, June-1991, May
    - Hebrew University Health Insurance Fund, 1991, Mar.-1994, Dec.
    - Hebrew University Pension Fund, 1988, Jan.-1989, Dec.
    - Hebrew University Professors' Association, 1994, Dec.-1995, Jan.
    - Hebrew University: Salary/Pension, 1994, June-July
    - International Economic Association, 1992, Sept.-1994, Oct.
    - Ilana Pardes, 1989-1993,Apr. (Box 65)
    - Income Tax, 1988, Jan.-1995, Feb.
    - Invitations, 1984, Aug.-1995, Jan.
    - Israel Prize, 1986, July-1990, July
    - Italian Academy, 1991, Aug.-1994, Jan.
    - Italy, 1988, Oct.-1995, May
    - Jerome Levy Institute, 1993, Nov.-1994, Dec.
    - Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, 1994, Sept.-1995, July
    - Johnson, Ivan, 1993, Aug. 11-23
    - Jonung, Lars, 1993, Feb.-1995, July
    - Kahn, Richard, 1983, Feb.-1993, June
    - Kates, Steven, 1992, Sept.-1995, Apr.
    - Keynes and his Interpreters, 1995, Feb.-1995, June
    - Keynes Book Reviews, 1989, Dec. 5
    - Keynes Papers, 1990-1992
    - King, Mervyn, 1993, Oct.-1994, Apr.
    - Kings College Library, 1990, May-1994, Aug.
    - Kornacker, Thomas, 1994, Apr.
    - Kregel, Jan. A., 1988, Sept.-1992, Apr.
    - Krueger, Harvey, 1986, Aug.-1993, July
    - Kupat Holim- Meuhedet Health Insurance, 1994, Dec.-1995, Mar.
    - Kuznets, Edith, 1965, Jan.-1992, Aug.
    - Kuznets, Paul, 1992, Sept.
    - Lady Davis Trust, 1994, June-1995, July
    - Laidler, David, 1994, July-1995, Aug.
    - Lancaster, Kelvin, 1986, Oct.-1994, Dec.
    - Landes, David, 1991, Mar.-1994, Jan.
    - Latsis Foundation, 1990, June-1995, July
    - Leijonhufvud, Axel 1974, Feb.-1992, Mar.
    - Levy, Margot, 1991, Nov.-1993, Sept.
    - Library, 1989, Dec.-1995, July
    - Liebenson, Joseph, 1982, Oct.-1994, Aug.
    - Lucas, Robert E., 1993, Feb.-1995, May
    - Lundberg, 1987, Sept.-1995, Apr.
    - Maital, Shlomo, 1992, May-1992, July
    - Marty, Alvin, 1993, July-1994, Jan.
    - McCloskey, Donald, 1989, July-1992, July
    - Mikesell, Raymond, 1952, Aug.-1995, May
    - Miscellaneous - Others, 1994, May-1995, July
    - Miscellaneous - Professional, 1995, Jan.-1995, May
    - MIT Press: Terry Vaughn, 1994, Feb.-1995, June
    - Moetza L'Shalom (Peace Council), 1988, July-1995, July (Box 66)
    - Moggridge, D.E., 1993, July-1995, July
    - Moscow School, 1994-1995
    - Moscow School,1995
    - Mundlak, Yair, 1995, May
    - Naama, 1993, July-1994, Aug.
    - Negishi, Takashi, 1991, Sept.-1994, Jan.
    - New Palgrave, 1985, Mar.-1991, Apr.
    - Nobel, 1988, Nov.-1995, Jan.
    - Norway, 1990, June-1991, Feb.
    - National Science Foundation, 1989, Apr.-1993, June
    - Opera, 1990-1992
    - Osiatynski, Jerzy, 1988, Apr.-1993, Oct.
    - Ostroy, Joe, 1994, Apr.
    - Pasinetti, Luigi, 1995, Jan.-1995, Feb.
    - Patinkin Fund, 1988, May-1991, Mar.
    - Patinkin Personal, 1954, May-1994, Nov.
    - Patinkin Politics, 1992, May-1994, July
    - Patinkin, Sheldon,Norman, Harold, 1988, May-1995, June
    - Permissions, 1985, Jan.-1994, June
    - Presley, John R., 1993, Mar.-1994, Nov.
    - Radio, 1995, Sept.-Apr.
    - Referee Reports, 1993, Feb.-1995, Feb.
    - Research Grant 049, 1989, Oct.-1995, Apr.
    - Research Funds, 1993, Jan.
    - Research Proposals, 1986, Nov.-1993, May
    - Reviews,Money, Interest, and Prices, No. 3, 1990, Jan.-1992
    - Roncaglia, Alessandro, 1989, Sept.-1995, Sept.
    - Routledge, 1991, Mar.-1993, Nov.
    - Royalties, 1987, Mar.-1994, Mar.
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 1995, Mar.-1995, May
    - Sachs, Jeff, 1993, Nov.
    - Sandilands, Roger, 1994, Nov.-1994, Dec.
    - Sebastiani, Mario, 1990, May-1994, Apr.
    - Selgin, George, 1994, Oct.-1994, Feb.
    - Seminar: Keynes, 1978-1990
    - Shepherd, George B. (Gans and Shepherd), 1992, Apr.-1994, Aug.
    - Sheshinski, Eytan, 1989, May-1993, Oct.
    - Skidelsky, Robert, 1992, Dec.-1995, May
    - Skolnick, Irving, 1994, Mar.-1995, Jan.
    - Steiger, Otto, 1989, May-1993, Aug.
    - Stein, Herbert, 1990, July-1993, June
    - Steindl, Frank G., 1991, Jan.-1993, Dec.
    - Steve, Sergio, 1992, June-1992, Sept. (Box 67)
    - Subscriptions, 1991, Mar.-1995, June
    - Sweden,1993, June-Dec.
    - Tobin, James, 1995, Feb.-1995, Mar.
    - Turkey, 1993, Apr.-1993, July
    - Viner, Jacob, 1972
    - Wake Forest Conference, 1993, Dec.-1994, Aug.
    - Walras Center, 1987, Jan.-1995, Feb.
    - Whitaker, John K., 1989, Jan.-1993, Aug.
    - Who's Who, 1987, Dec.-1995, Aug.
    - Witztum, Amos, 1992, Dec.-1995, Jan.
    - Young, Warren, 1995, Feb.-1995, Jan.
    - Zamagni, Stefano, 1988, Oct.-1993, Jan.
    - Zawadski, Wlodek, 1994, Jan.-1994, June
    - Zelinsky, Dan, 1993, Apr.-1995, Mar.
- Israel and Hebrew Series, ca. 1944-1986and undated
  Though almost all the materials are in Hebrew, many folders were marked by Patinkin with English titles. There are materials filed here whose subjects are related to other series above: for instance, Patinkin's Hebrew University course materials on general monetary theory are be found here rather than in the General Monetary Series. There are also numerous folders of correspondence in this series. Materials are not in date order.
  - Raw Materials Subseries
    - Israeli Economics Materials, 1964-1967 (Box 68)
    - National Council on Saving, 1966-1968
    - Reprints on "Brain Drain," 1963-1967
    - Project Proposal to Settle 10,000 Refugee Families in El-Erish,1967
    - Proposal to Settle 1800 Families in Patsal Region,1967
    - Survey on the Sociability Problems in the Occupied Territories,1967
    - Development of the Occupied Territories,1967("Secret")
    - Committee on the Development of Occupied Territories,1967, (2 folders)
    - The Refugee Problem, 1967
    - Israeli Economics Materials,1967
    - Rent-controlled Apts., Key Money, and the Tying of Rent to a Price Index, ca. 1968-70, (5 folders)
    - Israeli Economics, ca. 1966-1971
    - The Thrift Programs in the Years 1969-1955, 1973
    - Monetary and Price Developments,1944-1953(Original Draft) (Box 69)
    - Transportation Geography Study
    - E. E. C., 1957, Feb.-1958, May
    - Monetary and Price Developments in Israel
    - Committee for Examining Government Economic Planning and Advisory Officers,1958
    - State of Israel, Office of the Government, the Copy - Yehuda Grunfeld,1949
    - S.J. Prais, 1957, Oct.-1959, June
    - Comments on Report on the Economy of Israel,1955, Aug.-1960, Feb.
    - Statistics, 1959-1960
    - Yehuda Grunfeld - Nigeria Development: Nonparametric tests for time series
    - Nigeria Development,1959
    - Transportation Center,1959
    - Bank of Israel, 1960, Mar.-1963, Oct.
    - Trinity for Dr. Yehuda Grunfeld,1960
    - Yehuda Grunfeld Dictations,1960
    - National Council for Research and Development
    - Falk Project for Economic Research in Israel (Agriculture), 1960-1962
    - Falk Project on Agriculture, 1962-1963
    - Various Course Outlines, Statistical Reports and Worksheets, 1961-1970
    - Advisory Committee for Economic and Sociological Research in Cooperation with the Liszt Institute, Basel
    - Press Cuttings re: the Patinkin Committee for Examining the Development. of Energy in
    - Israel, 1963, Oct.-1964, June
    - Committee to Examine the Problems of the Development of Electricity in Israel
    - 1963, Sept.-1964, July
    - D.P.'s Reaction to German Loan, 1966, May-June
    - The Story of the Western Economy "Guarded,"1967
    - Macroeconomics Exercises and Writings for Lectures, Part A
    - Symposium on the Security Budget (Box 70)
    - Material on Income of Salaried Workers,1972
    - Rent Article, Raw Material and Worksheets from1971Memo - Updated1972and Used for1972revision
    - Indexation 3,1974, (2 folders)
    - Indexation 2, 1974-1976, (3 folders)
    - Indexation 1, 1974-1975, (3 folders)
    - Reuben Brenner - Essays on Indexation
    - Israel and Palestine: Is a Common Market in the Common Interest? 1980
    - Israel Stabilization, 1984-1986
    - Defense Programming, ca. 1954-1962
    - Macroeconomic Theory in Open Economy (Writings for Lectures in Macroeconomics), Part B
    - Price Theory - Exercises, 1960-1961
    - Weiler, Supranationalism Revisited ... (Box 71)
    - The Crown of Wisdom, Vol. 1
    - The Crown of Wisdom, Vol. 2
    - Hebrew University, 1986, (3 folders)
    - Israel Stabilization- Raw Materials not used
    - Israel Stabilization- Raw Materials, A-K
    - Israel Stabilization- Raw Materials, HEB
    - Monetary and Price Development Materials (Box 72)
    - Hebrew Notes and Data,1973
    - Rent Article, Worksheets, Diagrams, and Typed Copies of First1972Revision
    - Maggie's Diagrams.
    - Rent article, Worksheets Used in1971memo - Not Relevant to1972Revision
    - Newspaper Clippings
    - Rent Article: Worksheets Underlying Final1972Revision
    - Progress Report 1970-1972,Israel Institute of Business Research, Tel Aviv Univ.
    - Various Israeli Statistics,1971
    - Rent Article1972: Final Revision, (2 folders)
    - Rent Article, 1971, Jan.-1973, Feb.
    - Israel Stabilization, Drafts and Revisions, (2 folders)
    - Israel Stabilization, Data and Diagrams, (2 folders)
    - Economic Welfare of Arab Population in Gaza, 1970
  - Course Materials Subseries
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Papers, 1949-1951 (Box 73)
    - Lecture Notes
    - Notes
    - Econ. 201 - Lecture Notes, etc.
    - Introduction to Economy
    - Seminar in Monetary Theory, Intermediate Test, 1964-1965
    - Intermediate Test on Progressive Economic Theory,1965
    - Class Notes and Tests, Manuscripts, 1952-1959
    - Class Tests and Notes, 1955-1958
    - Class Notes and Bibliographies, 1949-1959
    - Exams
    - Statistics Courses
    - Test on Price Theory
    - Trade Among Agriculture (bibliography, notes), 1949-1952
    - Seminar in Business Cycles, 1951-1957
    - Class Tests and Notes, 1951-1961
    - Tests in Progressive Economic Theory and Theory of Progressive Prices, 1953-1963
    - Tests: Introduction to the Economy, Economic Trends, History of the Economy,1959
    - Tests: Introduction to the Economy, Price Theory, Israeli Economics, 1958-1959
    - Tests: Economic Theory, Price Theory, Introduction to the Economy,1956
    - Final Exams, 1957-1963
    - Silvio Gesell, 1951-1965
    - Final Exams, 1960-1965
    - The Israeli Academy of Agricultural Sciences,1968
    - Final Exams, 1958-1960
    - Final Exams,1955, 1966, 1985
    - The Student's Committee of the Hebrew University in Jerusalem,1960 (Box 74)
    - Seminar in Monetary Theory,1969
    - Seminar Paper in Economics
    - Seminar Paper
    - Seminar Work
    - Macroeconomics (including syllabi from other professors), 1980-1981
    - Selective Control on Consumer Credit, Seminar Paper,1972
    - Final Paper from Amnon Yakuby
    - Influence on Market Price - The Theory and Reality in Israel, Seminar Paper,1985
    - Final Paper in Economics,1976
    - Monetary Seminar, 1974-1975
    - Correspondence, 1984-1986, (3 folders)
    - Shmuel Eisenstadt and Yaacor Katz,1963, 1987
    - Yehuda Grunfeld - Correspondence,1960, (2 folders)
    - Introduction to Economics
  - Other Materials Subseries
    - Monetary Seminar,1975 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, Reports from David Horovitz Institute, The Foeder Institute, etc.,1973
    - Banks,1959
    - Press,1971
    - Curriculum Vitae,1972, (2 folders)
    - Readings
    - The Israeli Academy of Agriculture, 1977
    - Journal and Newspaper Articles, Reports, Proposals in Hebrew
    - Lectures on Research,1958
    - Arab/Israeli Labor Force
    - Committee to Develop the Occupied Territories, Panel to Planning Social Economy/
    - Occupied Territory Dvt., Alternative Inspection, "Secret," undated
    - Studies to Find Range Short Circuit, undated
    - State of Israel Security Office; Committee to Develop the Occupied Territories, Inspection
    - "Secret," undated
    - Israel Lecture Materials
    - Exam Questions
    - The State of Israel Security Office,1970
    - Bank of Israel, The State of Israel Security Office, Central Office for Statistics, "Restricted," 1969-1970
    - Gathering to Remember Dr. Prader,1973
    - Israeli Worker, 1950
    - The Committee to Develop the Occupied Territories, Panel to Planning Social Economy/Dvt. of Occupied Territories, Inspection, "Secret,"1967
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence,1972
- Miscellaneous Series, ca. 1930-1990and undated (Bulk 1950-1980)
  Contains materials which could not be filed easily with other series in this collection. Includes many copies of articles by Patinkin as well as by others on various miscellaneous topics. Also contains some folders of biographical data and photographs. Materials are not in date order.
  - Other Writings and Speeches Subseries
    - U.S. and British Statistics, 1930-1960, (3 folders) (Box 76)
    - Conference on Brain Drain,1967
    - Who's Who in Israel, 1978
    - Patinkin Resumes
    - Facts and Figures on Migration of Talent and Skills,1966-1967
    - Brain Drain As It Affects the Philippines Migration of Health Personnel, Scientists, and Engineers from Latin America, 1966-1967
    - Econometric Society, Lecture 1
    - Econometric Society, Lecture 2
    - Econometric Society, Lecture 3
    - Autobiography: Section 1-Raw Materials (Box 77)
    - Autobiography: Section 2-Raw Materials
    - Patinkin Articles, (2 folders)